<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Fireworks on end2end zone</title>
    <link>http://www.end2endzone.com/tags/fireworks/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Fireworks on end2end zone</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 07 Dec 2014 06:49:09 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://www.end2endzone.com/tags/fireworks/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>How to photograph fireworks with a DSLR camera</title>
      <link>http://www.end2endzone.com/how-to-photograph-fireworks-with-a-dslr-camera/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Dec 2014 06:49:09 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://www.end2endzone.com/how-to-photograph-fireworks-with-a-dslr-camera/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;introduction&#34;&gt;Introduction&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Do you plan to take photographs of fireworks during the next few weeks? If so you might take a look at this article that explains how to properly shoot fireworks with a DSLR camera.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Getting a nice firework picture is it not as simple as going outside, finding a firework display and starting to shoot bits of lights in the sky. There are things you can do to increase your chances of success or fine tune the end result.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Of course, it is also temping to take picture of the fireworks with a decent phone or point &amp;amp; shoot camera if you have a &amp;ldquo;firework&amp;rdquo; option, but those kind of picture often comes out as grainy/noisy or worst blurry.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In this article, I will guide you to make the most stunning photography of fireworks with your DSLR camera.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mes attentes et toutes ces choses que je veux photographier</title>
      <link>http://www.end2endzone.com/mes-attentes-et-toutes-ces-choses-que-je-veux-photographier/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Aug 2014 00:36:44 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://www.end2endzone.com/mes-attentes-et-toutes-ces-choses-que-je-veux-photographier/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Ce que j&amp;rsquo;attends de la photographie? Je ne sais pas vraiment. C&amp;rsquo;est un passe-temps après tout, mais au fil du temps, j&amp;rsquo;ai réussi à réfléchir à des choses agréable à photographier. La plupart d&amp;rsquo;entre elles sont des défis techniques, mais certains d&amp;rsquo;entre elles ont un niveau de difficulté géographique. D&amp;rsquo;autres ne sont possibles que pendant une période spécifique de l&amp;rsquo;année.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Voici ma liste de ce que je voudrais réussir à capturer avec ma caméra:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>My expectations and things I would like to shoot</title>
      <link>http://www.end2endzone.com/my-expectations-and-things-i-would-like-to-shoot/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Aug 2014 10:20:35 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://www.end2endzone.com/my-expectations-and-things-i-would-like-to-shoot/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;What I expect from photography? I don&amp;rsquo;t really know. It&amp;rsquo;s a hobby after all but over time I managed to think about cool things I would like to shoot. Most of them are technical challenges but some of them have a geographical difficulty level. Others are only possible during a specific period of the year.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Here is my list of what I would hunt for a good shoot:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
