<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Freeware on end2end zone</title><link>http://localhost:1313/tags/freeware/</link><description>Recent content in Freeware on end2end zone</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 29 Mar 2015 20:00:07 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/freeware/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>extTools: a windows shell extension to help you with common Windows File Explorer tasks.</title><link>http://localhost:1313/exttools-a-windows-shell-extension-to-help-you-with-common-windows-file-explorer-tasks/</link><pubDate>Sun, 29 Mar 2015 20:00:07 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://localhost:1313/exttools-a-windows-shell-extension-to-help-you-with-common-windows-file-explorer-tasks/</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="what-is-exttools">What is extTools&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>extTools is a fast and innovative FREEWARE (for non-commercial use) software suite to help you executing common tasks in Windows File Explorer more easily.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It&amp;rsquo;s main features are:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Advanced clipboard support (copy, append or modify).&lt;/li>
&lt;li>File operation queuing (batch copy or paste).&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Better &amp;amp; quicker file deletions.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Powerful file renaming algorithms.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>XP like search tool (simple search tool).&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Extends Windows File Explorer by registering as a Shell Extension.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>extTools allows its users to execute tasks that are not available in a default Windows environment. extTools is also designed to replace existing task that are badly designed, annoying to execute or simply missing.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>HDHomeRun TV Dump: Unleash the DVR capabilities of your free to air live TV stream</title><link>http://localhost:1313/hdhomerun-tv-dump-unleash-the-dvr-capabilities-of-your-free-to-air-live-tv-stream/</link><pubDate>Mon, 16 Feb 2015 02:24:14 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://localhost:1313/hdhomerun-tv-dump-unleash-the-dvr-capabilities-of-your-free-to-air-live-tv-stream/</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="hdhomerun-tv-dump">HDHomeRun TV Dump&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>&lt;em>HdHomeRun TV Dump&lt;/em> is a &lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Graphical_user_interface">GUI&lt;/a> that installs over the native &lt;a href="http://www.silicondust.com/support/downloads/">HDHomeRun application&lt;/a> and allows owners to quickly take control over the free to air live TV stream. Implementing DVR capabilities on your computer becomes a easy as 1-2-3.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It is designed to make interaction with the device easy by automating as much as possible any task a user would like to execute.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It&amp;rsquo;s main features are:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Quicker &amp;amp; easier to understand and install than other DVR solutions like &lt;a href="https://www.mythtv.org/">MythTV&lt;/a> and &lt;a href="http://windows.microsoft.com/en-CA/windows/products/windows-media-center">Windows Media Center&lt;/a>.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Auto-detection of existing HDHomeRun devices on the network.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Auto-detection of busy tuners.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Automatic selection of an available tuner for watching or recording a live TV stream.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Manual recording support.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Scheduled recording support (enables DVR capabilities with the HDHomeRun)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Watch live TV streams.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>&lt;em>HDHomeRun TV Dump&lt;/em> should also work with devices that supports the MPEG4/H.264 video codec but this functionality is still untested.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>DNS-343 Monitor: Easily monitors disk space on your DNS-343 NAS.</title><link>http://localhost:1313/dns-343-monitor-easily-monitors-disk-space-on-your-dns-343-nas/</link><pubDate>Sun, 01 Feb 2015 13:58:08 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://localhost:1313/dns-343-monitor-easily-monitors-disk-space-on-your-dns-343-nas/</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="dns343monitor">DNS343Monitor&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>DNS-343 Monitor is a tool for monitoring how much space is left on your DNS-343 NAS device.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The &lt;a href="http://www.google.com/?q=dns-343">DNS-343&lt;/a> is a &lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Network-attached_storage">Network Attached Storage&lt;/a> (NAS) device that can hold as much as 4 drives. Since all the drives are shared in a Network, each disk can quickly become full. This tools allows you to see the remaining space left on each individual drives.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It&amp;rsquo;s main features are:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Show space left and used for each drives.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>GUI supported.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Compatible with all firmware versions.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p class="pleasenote">
 &lt;strong>Note:&lt;/strong> This tool requires administrator privileges on the DNS-343 for retrieving free space left.
&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>MSBuildReorder: How to reorder a Visual Studio build log for easy reading</title><link>http://localhost:1313/msbuildreorder-how-to-reorder-a-visual-studio-build-log-for-easy-reading/</link><pubDate>Sat, 31 Jan 2015 01:27:33 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://localhost:1313/msbuildreorder-how-to-reorder-a-visual-studio-build-log-for-easy-reading/</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="msbuildreorder">MSBuildReorder&lt;/h1>
&lt;p class="postedit">
 Please note that MSBuildReorder source code is now moved to GitHub. Source code can be downloaded from &lt;a href="http://github.com/end2endzone/msbuildreorder">the project&amp;rsquo;s GitHub page&lt;/a>.
&lt;/p>
&lt;p>
&lt;img src="https://img.shields.io/badge/License-MIT-yellow.svg" alt="">


&lt;img src="https://img.shields.io/github/release/end2endzone/msbuildreorder.svg" alt="">


&lt;img src="https://ci.appveyor.com/api/projects/status/911ry08o97ubv506/branch/master?svg=true" alt="">


&lt;img src="https://img.shields.io/appveyor/tests/end2endzone/msbuildreorder/master.svg" alt="">


&lt;img src="https://img.shields.io/github/downloads/end2endzone/msbuildreorder/total.svg" alt="">
&lt;/p>
&lt;p>MSBuildReorder is a tool for &amp;ldquo;reordering&amp;rdquo; (buildorder) a multi-process C++ build log. It allows a developer to convert the build log as if it was generated with a single processor.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Building a solution that has multiple projects can quickly become bloated with too many lines that are not related to each other. For this reason, finding the actual cause of a build fail is harder than it should be. MSBuildReorder is able to read the log and reorder the projects in a sequential order.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>OfficeReadOnly: How to open Microsoft Office documents as read-only</title><link>http://localhost:1313/officereadonly-how-to-open-microsoft-office-documents-as-read-only/</link><pubDate>Wed, 28 Jan 2015 02:12:41 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://localhost:1313/officereadonly-how-to-open-microsoft-office-documents-as-read-only/</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="officereadonly">OfficeReadOnly&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>OfficeReadOnly is a tool that allows a user to open any Office Documents as a Read-Only document directly from the File Explorer.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It&amp;rsquo;s main features are:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Integrates into Windows File Explorer or the with the &amp;ldquo;Send to&amp;rdquo; folder.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Supports Documents, Workbooks, Presentations and Diagrams.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Supports both Microsoft Office 2003 (*.doc) and Microsoft Office 2010 file extensions (*.doc, and *.docx).&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Can be used from the command prompt.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>Microsoft Office does not supports opening files as read-only when right-clicking a document from the File Explorer menu and it does not support opening file as read-only from the command prompt.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>bin2cpp: The easiest way to embed small files into a C++ executable</title><link>http://localhost:1313/bin2cpp-the-easiest-way-to-embed-small-files-into-a-c-executable/</link><pubDate>Mon, 12 Jan 2015 03:56:17 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://localhost:1313/bin2cpp-the-easiest-way-to-embed-small-files-into-a-c-executable/</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="bin2cpp">bin2cpp&lt;/h1>
&lt;p class="postedit">
 Please note that bin2cpp source code is now moved to GitHub. Source code can be downloaded from &lt;a href="http://github.com/end2endzone/bin2cpp">the project&amp;rsquo;s GitHub page&lt;/a>.
&lt;/p>
&lt;p>
&lt;img src="https://img.shields.io/badge/License-MIT-yellow.svg" alt="">


&lt;img src="https://img.shields.io/github/release/end2endzone/bin2cpp.svg" alt="">


&lt;img src="https://ci.appveyor.com/api/projects/status/q9k0ebb971o475qi/branch/master?svg=true" alt="">


&lt;img src="https://img.shields.io/appveyor/tests/end2endzone/bin2cpp/master.svg" alt="">


&lt;img src="https://img.shields.io/github/downloads/end2endzone/bin2cpp/total.svg" alt="">
&lt;/p>
&lt;p>bin2cpp is a command line tool for embedding small files (like images, icons or raw data files) into a C++ executable.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It&amp;rsquo;s main features are:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Easily converts small files as C++ source code for embedding into a C++ executable.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Content extraction supported by a unique function call for each embedded file.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Supports a multiple embedded files at once.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Makes it harder for resource hacker to modify or steal the embedded files.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>No third party libraries required for retrieving the data of the embedded files.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>bin2cpp is not implemented using &lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Resource_%28Windows%29">executable resources&lt;/a>. Instead, bin2cpp creates multiple function calls for retrieving the data which makes it harder to steal the executable&amp;rsquo;s content. It also makes it even harder to replace an existing resource of the executable.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>