<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>RC Transmitter on end2end zone</title><link>https://end2endzone.github.io/tags/rc-transmitter/</link><description>Recent content in RC Transmitter on end2end zone</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 30 Mar 2016 17:15:24 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://end2endzone.github.io/tags/rc-transmitter/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>How to multiplex RC Transmitter switches into a single channel</title><link>https://end2endzone.github.io/how-to-multiplex-rc-transmitter-switches-into-a-single-channel/</link><pubDate>Wed, 30 Mar 2016 17:15:24 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://end2endzone.github.io/how-to-multiplex-rc-transmitter-switches-into-a-single-channel/</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="introduction">Introduction&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>In a personal project, I wanted to add 2 new devices to an existing quadcopter. The quadcopter was equipped with a 6-channel receiver meaning I only had 1 spare channel to control the 2 devices:&lt;/p>
&lt;div class="rc-channels">
 &lt;table>
 &lt;thead>
 &lt;tr>
 &lt;th>&lt;/th>
 &lt;th>&lt;/th>
 &lt;th>&lt;/th>
 &lt;/tr>
 &lt;/thead>
 &lt;tbody>
 &lt;tr>
 &lt;td>CH 1&lt;/td>
 &lt;td>:&lt;/td>
 &lt;td>Throttle&lt;/td>
 &lt;/tr>
 &lt;tr>
 &lt;td>CH 2&lt;/td>
 &lt;td>:&lt;/td>
 &lt;td>Rudder&lt;/td>
 &lt;/tr>
 &lt;tr>
 &lt;td>CH 3&lt;/td>
 &lt;td>:&lt;/td>
 &lt;td>Ailerons&lt;/td>
 &lt;/tr>
 &lt;tr>
 &lt;td>CH 4&lt;/td>
 &lt;td>:&lt;/td>
 &lt;td>Elevator&lt;/td>
 &lt;/tr>
 &lt;tr>
 &lt;td>CH 5&lt;/td>
 &lt;td>:&lt;/td>
 &lt;td>Flight mode&lt;/td>
 &lt;/tr>
 &lt;tr>
 &lt;td>CH 6&lt;/td>
 &lt;td>:&lt;/td>
 &lt;td>???&lt;/td>
 &lt;/tr>
 &lt;/tbody>
&lt;/table>

&lt;/div>
&lt;p>The following article explains how I manage to solve the issue: &lt;em>How can I control more than one device using a single channel&lt;/em>.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>RcReceiverSignal: an arduino library for retrieving the RC Transmitter value from an RC Receiver pulse</title><link>https://end2endzone.github.io/rcreceiversignal-an-arduino-library-for-retreiving-the-rc-transmitter-value-from-an-rc-receiver-pulse/</link><pubDate>Wed, 30 Mar 2016 17:05:59 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://end2endzone.github.io/rcreceiversignal-an-arduino-library-for-retreiving-the-rc-transmitter-value-from-an-rc-receiver-pulse/</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="introduction">Introduction&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>The following arduino library was written to use the findings found during the &lt;em>&lt;strong>&lt;a href="https://end2endzone.github.io/mapping-rc-transmitter-pwm-signal-to-actual-transmitter-values/">Mapping RC Transmitter PWM signal to actual transmitter values&lt;/a>&lt;/strong>&lt;/em> article. All results were wrapped into a library for ease of use.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The RcReceiverSignal is an arduino library that allows one to read a signal sent from a Remote Controlled (RC) receiver.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Skip to the &lt;a href="https://end2endzone.github.io/rcreceiversignal-an-arduino-library-for-retreiving-the-rc-transmitter-value-from-an-rc-receiver-pulse/#Download">download section&lt;/a> for quick download.&lt;/p>
&lt;h1 id="purpose">Purpose&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>The RcReceiverSignal library allows one to easily configure an input pin to read a PWM signal sent from a RC receiver by attaching a RcReceiverSignal instance to a pin connected the receiver and automatically monitor each pulse sent by the receiver.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Mapping RC Transmitter PWM signal to actual transmitter values</title><link>https://end2endzone.github.io/mapping-rc-transmitter-pwm-signal-to-actual-transmitter-values/</link><pubDate>Sat, 26 Mar 2016 20:47:29 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://end2endzone.github.io/mapping-rc-transmitter-pwm-signal-to-actual-transmitter-values/</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="introduction">Introduction&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>If you ever need to use an RC Transmitter &amp;amp; receiver for a personal project, an easy way to retrieve the signal is to connect the receiver to a micro-controller.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>However, decoding the signal to get actual transmitter values is not as easy as it sounds. You need to know the correct encoding and searching on the internet about the subject gives erratic results.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Here is the full article that explains how to correctly map an RC Transmitter PWM signal to actual transmitter values.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Demystifying RC Transmitter Mixing</title><link>https://end2endzone.github.io/demystifying-rc-transmitter-mixing/</link><pubDate>Thu, 28 Jan 2016 17:44:31 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://end2endzone.github.io/demystifying-rc-transmitter-mixing/</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="introduction">Introduction&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>If you look on the internet for &amp;ldquo;mixing&amp;rdquo;, you will usually find posts and articles of people asking for things like &amp;ldquo;what is the best mix I should use for this or that&amp;rdquo; which I think is not helpful. I think it is far more helpful to actually understand what mixing is and how it can help you improve your skills as a pilot. Lately I wanted to understand how mixing could help me in a personal project. I took this opportunity to learn something new and try to demystifying RC Transmitter Mixing.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>RC Transmitter Mix Calculator</title><link>https://end2endzone.github.io/rc-transmitter-mix-calculator/</link><pubDate>Thu, 28 Jan 2016 17:43:43 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://end2endzone.github.io/rc-transmitter-mix-calculator/</guid><description>&lt;p>This is an Excel worksheet I created based on the calculations I found for calculating most R/C Transmitter mixes. It is designed to help you identify the effective range of a mix (finding the low, medium and high values).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>See my post on &lt;a href="https://end2endzone.github.io/demystifying-rc-transmitter-mixing/">Demystifying RC Transmitter Mixing&lt;/a> for more details.&lt;/p>
&lt;p class="pleasenote">
 Please note the following calculator is valid on Spektrum Transmitters. I did not verified it&amp;rsquo;s validity or accuracy on other transmitters.
&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>